<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris Downing</title>
    <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris Downing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Chris Downing 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Raspberry Pi Cluster</title>
      <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/bramble-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/bramble-intro/</guid>
      <description>People have been building clusters using the Raspberry Pi family of devices for years now - the first example I came across was “Iridis-pi”, which serves as a demonstrator system for clustered computing and a classic example of how adults will find almost any excuse to play with Lego as part of their day job.
In the past, I have built a 4-node cluster using RPi2 devices - within that build, I used the official Raspbian OS and set up the SLURM job scheduler and GlusterFS distributed storage service - both from official repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XCP-ng</title>
      <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/xcp-ng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/xcp-ng/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, the XCP-ng project completed a round of crowd-funding to produce a fully open version of XenServer without any paid feature lock-down.
This is a project I was pretty excited about; although I had never tried XenServer or any VMWare tools common to enterpriste IT, I was keen to have a more flexible &amp;ldquo;home lab&amp;rdquo; setup than the bunch of RPi&amp;rsquo;s and regular servers I&amp;rsquo;d accumulated. ProxMox was my first attempt at running a virtualised setup at home, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t enjoyed the experience much - I wanted something which would require less tinkering, ideally with a more modern interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minio</title>
      <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/minio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/minio/</guid>
      <description>Minio is a simple, S3 compatible object storage server which can be deployed in a Docker container or as a simple binary and provides built-in deduplication over objects.
The application design is very much aligned with the in-vogue microservices model - configuration is fairly minimal, and in the simplest case Minio can be launched using just a filesystem path in which the objects are to be stored. Each instance of Minio effectively operates in &amp;ldquo;single-user&amp;rdquo; mode, with one access key/secret key pair - in order to offer Minio to multiple users from the same server or cluster, the administrator need only deploy more Minio instances targeting a different directory per user (or &amp;ldquo;tenant&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, world</title>
      <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/hello/</guid>
      <description>This is a place for me to put written content which doesn&amp;rsquo;t have another home. Mostly, it&amp;rsquo;ll be technically-focused, perhaps with some commentary on blogs, articles and white papers I&amp;rsquo;ve written elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the author</title>
      <link>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisdowning.co.uk/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>Chris Downing is a UK-based consultant focused on the high-performance computing (HPC) industry.
He hates writing about himself in the third person.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>